<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nina Flores</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nina Flores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me and Computational Biology</title>
      <link>/blog/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/post/</guid>
      <description>Every time I tell people that my major is computational biology, I’m met with blank stares as I attempt to answer their questions about this field. So, for my first post, I’ll actually show everyone some of what compuational biologists do. About In my Computational Biology and Bioinformatics course (SDS348), we dove into topics of data visualization, probability functions, data manipulation and wrangling, matrices, distances, associations, clustering, PCA, hypothesis testing, simulation, ANOVA, MANOVA, PERMANOVA, linear regression, logistic regression, binary classification, cross validation and regularization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA Project</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>I obtained two datasets containing information about recent movies. As an avid movie goer, who is a proud AMC A-list member and an alumni of Moviepass (may it rest in peace), I was interested in seeing the relationships between various movie production companies, actors, budgets, genres, and success in the box office. Both datasets were obtained from kaggle (movies from Daniel Grijalva and IMDb from PrompCloud). The IMDb dataset contains information from 2006-2016 for the 1,000 most popular movies and 12 variables including rank, title, genre, description, actors, year, runtime, votes, rating, revenue, and metascore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Project</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Nina Flores This data comes from a survey that Dr. Fatima Varner’s African American Resilience in Context lab in the Department of Human Development and Family Sciences conducted. The survey has responses from 324 black mothers and 252 black fathers with an adolescent child between 11-18. The survey had over 300 questions targeting various social constructs covering topics of school involvement, parenting behaviors, racial concerns, and racial discrimination. The variables of interest for this project include: ‘PA_EDU’, ‘PART_EDU’, ‘MARSTAT’, ‘TOTIVP’, ‘vicarious’, ‘pdisc’, ‘cdisc’, ‘TOTRCON’, ‘totbpi’, ‘NEIGHCOMP’, ‘JOBCOMP’, ‘SCHCOMP’, ‘TOTINC’, ‘recodedgpa’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Here are some projects I have been working on:
 Data Wrangling and Exploratory Analysis: An Exploratory Data Analysis on IMDb movie data for all the movie lovers like me.
  Modeling, Inference, Prediction: Statistical Modeling of K-12 school-based marginalization targeting topics of child discrimination, problem behaviors, and demographics.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>