<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nina Flores</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nina Flores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA Project</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>I obtained two datasets containing information about recent movies. As an avid movie goer, who is a proud AMC A-list member and an alumni of Moviepass (may it rest in peace), I was interested in seeing the relationships between various movie production companies, actors, budgets, genres, and success in the box office. Both datasets were obtained from kaggle (movies from Daniel Grijalva and IMDb from PrompCloud). The IMDb dataset contains information from 2006-2016 for the 1,000 most popular movies and 12 variables including rank, title, genre, description, actors, year, runtime, votes, rating, revenue, and metascore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Link to project 1
R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&#39;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&#39;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&#39;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Nina M. Flores nina.m.flores@icloud.com 817.789.5900 Austin, TX
EDUCATION UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS
Austin, TX Bachelor of Science in Computational Biology May 2020 Certificate in Scientific Computation and Data Sciences College of Natural Sciences Overall GPA: 3.91/4.00
 RESEARCH EXPERIENCE 9/2019-Current | Research Assistant/Data Analyst, African American Resilience in Context Lab, University | of Texas Department of Human Development and Family Sciences, Austin, TX | Advisor: Dr.Fatima Varner | Collaborate with PI to create personal project of conducting randomization, MANOVA, | regression, and logistic regression tests on relationships of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume1/</guid>
      <description>Nina M. Flores nina.m.flores@icloud.com 817.789.5900 Austin, TX
EDUCATION UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS
Austin, TX Bachelor of Science in Computational Biology May 2020 Certificate in Scientific Computation and Data Sciences College of Natural Sciences Overall GPA: 3.91/4.00
 RESEARCH EXPERIENCE 9/2019-Current | Research Assistant/Data Analyst, African American Resilience in Context Lab, University | of Texas Department of Human Development and Family Sciences, Austin, TX | Advisor: Dr.Fatima Varner | Collaborate with PI to create personal project of conducting randomization, MANOVA, | regression, and logistic regression tests on relationships of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Project</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Nina Flores, nmf538 This data comes from a survey that Dr. Fatima Varner’s African American Resilience in Context lab in the Department of Human Development and Family Sciences conducted. The survey has responses from 324 black mothers and 252 black fathers with an adolescent child between 11-18. The survey had over 300 questions targeting various social constructs covering topics of school involvement, parenting behaviors, racial concerns, and racial discrimination. The variables of interest for this project include: ‘PA_EDU’, ‘PART_EDU’, ‘MARSTAT’, ‘TOTIVP’, ‘vicarious’, ‘pdisc’, ‘cdisc’, ‘TOTRCON’, ‘totbpi’, ‘NEIGHCOMP’, ‘JOBCOMP’, ‘SCHCOMP’, ‘TOTINC’, ‘recodedgpa’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Projects Project 1 An Exploratory Data Analysis on IMDb movie data for all the movie lovers like me.
Project 2 Statistical Modeling of K-12 school based marginialization targeting topics of child discrimination, problem behaviors, and demographics.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>